<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>productivity - Tag - Janne "Lietu" Enberg</title><link>https://lietu.net/tags/productivity/</link><description>productivity - Tag - Janne "Lietu" Enberg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lietu.net/tags/productivity/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Please, sell me good services</title><link>https://lietu.net/2019/12/2019-12-24-please-sell-me-good-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://lietu.net/2019/12/2019-12-24-please-sell-me-good-services/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up identifying basically 2 services that I need both for personal use as well as work to be efficient and safe.
Cloud storage - ability to store files off my own computer and synchronize with all my computers
Password manager - generating and storing good passwords and giving me convenient access to them when I need it
It seems like these should be pretty widely wanted things, things that have been around for a long time, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of competition, yet I&amp;rsquo;ve been unable to find any good options.</description></item><item><title>Standard Windows development environment</title><link>https://lietu.net/2019/12/2019-12-21-standard-windows-development-environment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://lietu.net/2019/12/2019-12-21-standard-windows-development-environment/</guid><description><![CDATA[PrefacePreviously I&rsquo;ve written about how to develop &ldquo;like a pro&rdquo; on Windows with various tips and tricks about how to get your work optimized and solve common problems. Then I wrote Aperture Control to automate some of the common setup tasks for Windows.
Standard development environment for WindowsNow, using Aperture Control and based on the tips, I&rsquo;ve set up a repository to configure what I could consider a fairly standard development environment for Windows.]]></description></item><item><title>Introducing Aperture Control</title><link>https://lietu.net/2019/11/2019-11-12-introducing-aperture-control/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://lietu.net/2019/11/2019-11-12-introducing-aperture-control/</guid><description>I previously posted about how to &amp;ldquo;develop like a pro on Windows&amp;rdquo; as it seemed to me like most people really failed to understand that a lot of great tools exist for Windows that make developers very effective also on Windows.
Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve bumped into concepts like Nix, a purely functional package manager and have been wondering if we could reach some similar goals with Windows.
The things I wanted to see synchronized between all my Windows machines, and automated after a new installation were at least:</description></item><item><title>Developing like a pro, on Windows</title><link>https://lietu.net/2019/07/2019-07-11-developing-like-a-pro-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://lietu.net/2019/07/2019-07-11-developing-like-a-pro-on-windows/</guid><description>So it seems to me like a lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to value Windows for development. There seems to be a lot of misconceptions about it&amp;rsquo;s capabilities, availability of tooling, and lack of understanding of what really are the options.
This guide will hopefully help you guys see that Windows is a viable option just like anything else, and not just for C#. There&amp;rsquo;s also a few more generic tips about Windows use not purely useful in development.</description></item></channel></rss>